<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Abel Soares Siqueira</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Abel Soares Siqueira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://abelsiqueira.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CiDAMO</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.github.io/projects/cidamo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.github.io/projects/cidamo/</guid><description>At the Federal University of Paraná, while I was a professor, I helped create CiDAMO, a data science, machine learning, and optimization group. We created the group in 2018 (or 2017?) in order to attend to the increasing interest in data science from the students and from ourselves.
We organized a few events and meetups, although COVID really disrupted operations. In the beginning of 2020 we manage to have an in-person week-long event (called CiDWeek) with over 300 participants, with presentations from companies, professors, and students.</description></item><item><title>Jill</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.github.io/projects/jill/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.github.io/projects/jill/</guid><description>Jill is a command line installer for Julia. It works with Linux and OSX via bash, and you can quickly start using it with
curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/abelsiqueira/jill/main/jill.sh &amp;gt; jill.sh sudo bash jill.sh More in-depth The objectives of Jill are
One line installation of any Julia version; Easy to maintain/update when a new Julia version is released; Be lightweight with low dependencies. Whenever a version of Julia is installed, links are made to julia-x, julia-x.</description></item><item><title>JuliaSmoothOptimizers</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.github.io/projects/jso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.github.io/projects/jso/</guid><description>JuliaSmoothOptimizers (JSO) is an organization that I co-created with Dominique Orban around 2015 (or 14?) to store our optimization packages. The main idea of our packages is to enable high-quality development of optimization solvers, and it now contains over 60 packages. The main research area of JSO is nonlinear continuous optimization. Originally we looked only into twice differentiable problems, although that is changing a bit now, with some more general packages.</description></item><item><title>ThinkJulia</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.github.io/projects/thinkjulia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.github.io/projects/thinkjulia/</guid><description>I helped with the translation of the ThinkJulia book to Portuguese. I was involved managing the translation team with weekly meetings, and reviewing the submitted chapters.
The end result is available here: https://juliaintro.github.io/JuliaIntroBR.jl/.</description></item></channel></rss>