<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>linux on Abel Soares Siqueira</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in linux on Abel Soares Siqueira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abelsiqueira.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Gurobi 7 on Linux</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2017-03-13-installing-gurobi-7-on-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2017-03-13-installing-gurobi-7-on-linux/</guid><description>Disclaimer: What I did here might work on Windows or OSX, but I give no guarantee.
Request by Clóvis Gonzaga.
First, create an account here and login.
Secondly, download the appropriate Gurobi version clicking on Gurobi Optimizer. In my case, it is Linux 64 bits. Where to download this is optional, but you have to remember, as we&amp;rsquo;ll use later. I use a folder packages on my home folder.
Third, unpack the file.</description></item><item><title>New computer at work</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2015-11-16-new-computer-at-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2015-11-16-new-computer-at-work/</guid><description>I just got a new notebook at work. This is a HP computer, with a AMD a10-4600M processor, 4GB of RAM and 320GB of HD space. I have a personal notebook with a similar configuration and my work desktop also has a similar configuration, so this isn&amp;rsquo;t a great improvement. However, we&amp;rsquo;re gonna have an additional monitor, so this is good enough. Also, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the other one as the always-on screen+irssi computer.</description></item><item><title>Mudando de HD</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2014-12-19-mudando-de-hd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2014-12-19-mudando-de-hd/</guid><description>Ontem eu acabei de montar um computador novo. Esse computador é um upgrade do meu, e o meu passaria para a Kally. No entanto, eu não gostaria de perder a minha instalação dor Arch, nem de ficar com o HD antigo, então decidi tentar copiar as partições.
Nota: Não sei a aplicabilidade destes comandos para outras distribuições.
Nota: Você também poderia fazer o que fiz, usando o dd, mas eu preferi evitar.</description></item></channel></rss>