<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>jump on Abel Soares Siqueira</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/tags/jump/</link><description>Recent content in jump on Abel Soares Siqueira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abelsiqueira.com/tags/jump/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Optimizing the Dollar Game from Numberphile</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2018-09-04-the-dollar-game-from-numberphile/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2018-09-04-the-dollar-game-from-numberphile/</guid><description>I just watched The Dollar Game - Numberphile, in which a game involving graphs is presented. I recommend you watch the video for complete information.
The game involves a graph with integer values on its nodes, positive and negative. For instance, the following graph:
Each node corresponds to a person, the node value is the amount of money that person has, the edges are the people that person can give or take money from.</description></item><item><title>My experience in the JuMP-dev annual workshop</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2018-07-04-my-experience-in-the-jump-dev-annual-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2018-07-04-my-experience-in-the-jump-dev-annual-workshop/</guid><description>Last week I had the pleasure of being invited to the Second annual JuMP-dev workshop, which happened in June 27-29, 2018 at Bordeaux, France. I&amp;rsquo;ve presented the packages from the Julia Smooth Optimizers organization, and had a very good time meeting with the JuMP developers.
For those still unaware, JuMP is a modelling language for Mathematical Programming written in Julia. It provides access to a few different solvers for many kinds of problems, and it works inside of Julia, so one can enjoy the advantages of having a robust language if there is a need for advanced usage.</description></item></channel></rss>