<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fun on Abel Soares Siqueira</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/tags/fun/</link><description>Recent content in fun on Abel Soares Siqueira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abelsiqueira.com/tags/fun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Julia Fractal on Julia</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2017-01-15-julia-fractal-on-julia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2017-01-15-julia-fractal-on-julia/</guid><description>I wanted a background that would update automatically in some interesting way, instead of just random images. After some thought, I decided to use some Julia fractals.
I made a code to create the Julia fractals in the Julia language, and then some code to run it for a random point.
The code is here, including some explaining on how to use and install it.
Here are some examples:</description></item><item><title>Advent of Code 2016 in Julia</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2016-12-18-advent-of-code-2016-in-julia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2016-12-18-advent-of-code-2016-in-julia/</guid><description>Last year I discovered by chance a code competition that happens in the month of December: The Advent of Code. This event consists of small puzzles release every day of December, up to the 25th. Which amounts to 25 problems! (I can do math).
Last year I tried doing some on Bash, and latter switched to Julia, but never got to finish them. This year I decided to use Julia, because I want to test it for these general problems.</description></item><item><title>SiCLIPoD - Um Gerenciador de Podcasts Simples em Linha de Comando</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2014-12-11-siclipod-um-gerenciador-de-podcasts-simples-em-linha-de-comando/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2014-12-11-siclipod-um-gerenciador-de-podcasts-simples-em-linha-de-comando/</guid><description>Há algum tempo eu, esporadicamente, eu escuto o podcast do Jovem Nerd. Mas acessar o site é chato, então eu fui procurar um gerenciador de podcasts. Não gostei de nenhum (o gpodder quase foi escolhido). Daí, resolvi cria um no estilo que eu gosto. Falta MUITO pra ficar bom mas pode ser de alguma utilidade para alguém. O código está no GitHub. O básico pra funcionar é
siclipod add URL siclipod list siclipod list NAME siclipod search NAME STUFF siclipod download NAME STUFF siclipod play NAME STUFF O normal é tocar com o smplayer, mas você pode editar $HOME/.</description></item><item><title>Jogos de Tabuleiro</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2014-06-04-jogos-de-tabuleiro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2014-06-04-jogos-de-tabuleiro/</guid><description>Eu (não tão) recementemente me interessei em jogos de tabuleiro. Para clarificar, não estou me referindo aos jogos de tabuleiro &amp;ldquo;clássicos&amp;rdquo;, como War, Banco Imobiliário, etc.. Estou me referindo aos jogos de tabuleiro com mecânica avançada. Isso não significa que todos eles são complexos, mas que eles são (em sua maioria) bem pensados e balanceados. Esse jogos de tabuleiro juntaram uma legião de seguidores, a maioria geeks e nerds, que está interessada em algum hobby legal.</description></item></channel></rss>