<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>latex on Abel Soares Siqueira</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/tags/latex/</link><description>Recent content in latex on Abel Soares Siqueira</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abelsiqueira.com/tags/latex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A quasi-solution to my bib problem</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2016-08-21-a-quasi-solution-to-my-bib-problem/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2016-08-21-a-quasi-solution-to-my-bib-problem/</guid><description>For some time, one of my concerns is bibliography management. See my projects page if you have interest on working with something like that.
In the past, what we had was simply writing all your bibliographies directly on a .tex file. Then, if you needed to write again, you would copy-paste it somewhere. If you made a mistake, you would have to fix it by hand. If the journal changed styles, you would have to change everything by hand.</description></item><item><title>LaTeX tools for revision</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2016-03-06-latex-tools-for-revision/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2016-03-06-latex-tools-for-revision/</guid><description>This post is just to introduce two new tools I found.
LatexDiff is a tool that compares two tex files and generates a third marking the differences between them. It is great, for instance, when you update a thesis or article, and want to show the differences to your advisor or colleague.
Beware that this tool is not without mistakes. Sometimes it fails to mark a difference, specially in equations.</description></item><item><title>ShareLaTeX e o básico do cabeçalho</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2015-01-06-sharelatex-e-o-basico-do-cabecalho/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2015-01-06-sharelatex-e-o-basico-do-cabecalho/</guid><description>Este post serve principalmente para meus alunos e outros interessados em começar a usar o LaTeX. A primeira coisa a se notar é que instalar o compilador é bem chato e complicado, então sugiro usarem o ShareLaTeX que é um editor e compilador de LaTeX online. O ShareLaTeX possui uma boa documentação para quem está começando que infelizmente não está traduzida para português. Uma outra recomendação para quem está querendo ler sobre antes de começar a utilizar é http://en.</description></item><item><title>BibCLI - Command Line Interface to Manage Bibliography</title><link>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2014-06-04-bibcli/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abelsiqueira.com/blog/2014-06-04-bibcli/</guid><description>After working with references and citations in latex for a while, with multiple files, I noticed that some things need improvement. First of all, you need to use some way to store your bibliography outside of the tex file. For instance, using bibtex. Second, you probably want some bibliography package, such as biblatex or natbib. Third, you need some way to manage your bibliography entries and verify if they are correct.</description></item></channel></rss>